DANA HEIMANN

UX/UI & VISUAL DESIGNER

<u>Objective:</u> Seeking User Experience Design role with the opportunity to leverage my creative and managerial skills as I grow.

Design professional with strong user research, user interface and visual design skills with interests in Web Design, Project Management and Micro-interactions/animations. Completed Google User Experience Design Professional Certificate as well as Codecademy Pro's HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Color Design, Bootstrap, Sass, Navigation Design, & Responsive Design courses.

Excellent communication, time-management, and team-working skills with great attention to detail developed through years of experience working in various Michelin-star NYC restaurants.

Experienced English as a Second Language Teacher with demonstrated history of student success, creative lesson-planning, and self-scheduling. Bachelor's Degree in English Language & Literature, minors in Spanish Language & Art Studio Photography from the State University of New York at New Paltz.

CERTIFICATES (CODECADEMY)

LEARN JAVASCRIPT COURSE

November 2021

BUILD A WEBSITE WITH HTML, CSS,

& GITHUB PAGES SKILL PATH

October 2021

LEARN RESPONSIVE DESIGN

COURSE

September 2021

LEARN NAVIGATION DESIGN

COURSE

August 2021

LEARN SASS COURSE

July 2021

LEARN BOOTSTRAP COURSE

June 2021

LEARN COLOR DESIGN COURSE

June 2021

LEARN CSS COURSE

May 2021

LEARN HTML COURSE

November 2020

CONTACT



DANAHEIMANN.GITHUB.IO/

PORTFOLIO



DANA.C.HEIMANN

@GMAIL.COM



+34 658.68.86.37



SEVILLE, SPAIN



LINKEDIN.COM/IN/ DANAHEIMANN

GITHUB.COM/DANAHEIMANN

EDUCATION

GOOGLE USER EXPERIENCE DESIGN PROFESSIONAL

CERTIFICATE

Seville, Spain, 2023

STATE UNIVERSITY OF NEW

YORK AT NEW PALTZ

New Paltz, NY, USA, 2009-2013

Bachelor of Arts

Cum Laude

English Literature Major

Spanish & Art Studio Minors

GPA 3.6

UNIVERSIDAD DE SEVILLA

Seville, Spain, Spring 2012

Spanish Language Studies

GPA 4.0

UX / UI

- ♦ User Research
- ♦ User Journeys
- ♦ User Flow
- Sketchina
- Storyboarding
- Paper & Digital Wireframing
- ♦ Mockups

- ◆Affinity Mapping
- ♦ Mobile App Design Systems
- ♦ Lo-Fi & Hi-Fi Prototyping
- ♦ Usability **Studies**

DESIGN

- ♦ Fiama
- ❖ Adobe Suite (XD, Photoshop, ❖CSS Grid & Illustrator)
- ❖Typography
- ❖ Visual Hierarchy
 ❖ Bootstrap
- Color Theory

CODING

- ♣ HTMI
- **CSS**
- Flexbox
- ◆Basic JavaScript ◆ Problem
- Responsive Design

GENERAL

- Fluent Spanish
- ❖ Teaching
- ❖ Photography
- ❖ Leadership
- Solving
- ❖ Writing & Editing

WORK EXPERIENCE

ENGLISH CONNECTION TRIANA

(Private ESL Language Academy)

English as a Second Language Teacher

Seville, Spain ♦ September 2018 – June 2020

- Taught individual, group, and business classes to Spanish students from young learners to business professionals of all levels from beginner to advanced English. Taught a variety of skills including Reading, Listening, Speaking, Writing, Grammar, and Vocabulary
- Independently planned 16 lessons weekly, and managed all homework assignments, tests, writing assessments, and grading for 8 different classes

LE COUCOU (Fine Dining Restaurant with One Michelin Star & Winner of James Beard Award for Best New Restaurant in the United States, 2017)

Captain

New York, NY ♦ June 2017 - June 2018

- Managed and delegated tasks to a small section team to provide exceptional customer service and high-end fine-dining experience to guests. Utilized excellent time-management skills to plan and execute multiplecourse meals coordinated with wine pairings or bottle service with the ability to adapt on the fly as the service unfolded
- Helped guests select menu items through competent and thorough knowledge of all menu items, ingredients, sourcing locations, preparation techniques, & potential allergens and helped guests select wines by the glass through accurate knowledge of winemakers, regions, terroir, grape varietals, & vintages
- Constantly communicated with my team, managers and kitchen to provide elegant service, while using my ability to retain composure in a fast-paced, highpressure situation

AGERN (Fine Dining Restaurant with One Michelin Star)

Expeditor

New York, NY August 2016 - April 2017

- Maintained flow of service as acting liaison between front-of-house and back-of-house staff by coordinating the timing and firing of courses with the flexibility to adapt as new information was obtained. Delegated necessary tasks to kitchen servers and back servers while communicating openly and clearly with chefs, servers, and managers
- Gained comprehensive knowledge of all savory dishes, desserts, house-made cocktails & non-alcoholic drinks including each of their ingredients, why they were chosen, where they came from, how they were prepared, & what potential allergens they contained, and presented them to guests in a refined tableside manner

REBELLE (Fine Dining Restaurant with One Michelin Star)

Expeditor

New York, NY August 2015- July 2016

- Utilized excellent time management skills for timing and firing of dishes throughout a service of up to 200 guests per night by managing a constantly changing ticket board and effectively problem-solving to keep kitchen and dining rooms running smoothly simultaneously
- Communicated effectively with servers, sommeliers, and managers to accommodate needs, preferences, wine pairings, bottle service, allergies, and time constraints of guests, while at the same time worked closely with chefs & cooks to accommodate the needs of each kitchen station (Meat, Fish, Hot Appetizers, Cold Appetizers) accounting for preparation & plating times of all dishes as well as any unforeseen issues that might have arisen